Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising and Marketing Intelligence Database Records, 1977-1983 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising and Marketing Intelligence Database records 1977-1983 and undated
J. Walter Thompson Company.
1.8 linear feet Extent: 1125 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00661
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Advertising and Marketing Intelligence Database Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 1987.
Historical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company was founded in New York in 1864 and is one of the world's oldest and largest advertising firms.
Collection Overview
The J. Walter Thompson Company, Advertising and Marketing Intelligence Database Records date from 1977 to 1983, with some undated material. The collection contains information on the development and early years of the Advertising and Marketing Intelligence (AMI) database, successor to the Issues Monitoring System (1970s) produced by the New York Times (NYT) Information Bank and the White House; a JWT/NYT advertising and marketing news database (1979) drawn from over 60 major business publications; and AD/KIT, or Advertising Key Information Tracking System. Available by subscription and via telnet, AMI began in 1980 and tracked news items according to an advertising keyword index. The collection details the conception, announcement, and initial years of operation of AMI with financial data, marketing and management information, marketing research, and slide presentation scripts. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History.
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- Databases; Advertising -- United States -- History -- Databases; Marketing -- United States -- History -- Databases; Databases; Database management; Information storage and retrieval systems -- Marketing; Information storage and retrieval systems -- History; Information retrieval -- History; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2003-0218
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - AMI: Advertising and Marketing Intelligence User Guide, undated (Box 1)
    - Ad/K.I.T. I, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Speeches and Slides Materials
      - Information Management Speech, undated (Box 1)
      - AMI Speech [including original color photo, correspondence], 1980 (Box 1)
      - AMI Press Kit Originals [contains original color photograph], 1980 (Box 1)
      - Information management - Slide Presentation, undated (Box 1)
    - Advertising/Marketing Intelligence - Slide Presentation, 1980 (Box 1)
    - AMI Financial Info Revenues
      - AMI Revenue, 1980, 1981 (Box 1)
      - AMI Revenue Forecasts [1982 estimates] (Box 1)
      - Quarterly Profit Plan [for 1981, 1981 Apr. 28] (Box 1)
      - AMI Proposed Charge-Back Mechanism, 1981 (Box 1)
      - Profit Forecasts, Revenue Forecasts, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - AMI Marketing Plans and Reviews
      - AMI Issues and People, undated (Box 2)
      - AMI/MIS, 1981 (Box 2)
      - 3 Year Market Plan, 1981-1983, includes legal size but folded material (empty chart for Marketing Plan 1981-1983) (Box 2)
      - J. Peters/AMI Reviews, 1980, 1981 (Box 2)
      - Review of the AMI Relationship, 1981 June[including 1981 July] (Box 2)
      - Advertising/Marketing Intelligence [1980] (Box 2)
      - I-O-D: Business Plan, 1981 (Box 2)
      - Binder with misc. materials on AMI, 1980, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Projects
      - Speech, undated (Box 2)
      - MIS Creative Library Proposal, 1977, 1981 (Box 2)
      - SMRB Project, 1980 (Box 2)
      - Retail Info. Proposals, Worksheets, 1981 (Box 2)
      - User Committee [includes organizational proposal for Information Resource Management], 1980, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - AMI Promotional/Manuals AD Response
      - AMI Manuals [includes small and large glossy AMI brochures] (Box 3)
      - AMI Script, undated (Box 3)
      - [AMI misc.] (Box 3)
      - AMI-Japan (NKS), 1980 (Box 3)
      - AMI-Europe, 1980 (Box 3)
    - AMI Usage
      - Clients/ Survey/Contracts: J. Walter Thompson-New York Times Joint Venture, undated (Box 3)
      - The Advertising and Marketing Intelligence Data Base-Preliminary Market Study, undated (Box 3)
      - New York Times Information Bank Subscribers, undated (Box 3)
      - AMI Contract List, 1980, 1981 (Box 3)
      - AMI Client Usage, 1981 (Box 3)
      - AMI Usage: Returned Questionnaires, 1981 (2 folders) (Box 3)
      - AMI Usage: Database User Survey, 1980 (Box 3)